Now, let's bring it all together.
现在让我们把学过的东西串起来
Here is an example of what it could look like to create the animal API app
这个例子展示了如何创建应用访问 Animal
we'd been discussing with a UI that updates dynamically.
并且动态更新用户界面
So again first, let's test it out and make sure it works.
首先让我们看看它是否可以正常工作
Then if it does,
如果一切正常
we'll walk through the code to see exactly how it went.
我们就可以开始看代码了
So again, my favorite thing this time about lions are that lions are some of
这次我要输入 Lions are some of
the most thoughtful writing partners in the world as everyone knows.
the most thoughtful writing partners in the world
Now, on our webpage we have the animal lion.
页面上出现了 lion
Lions are fun fact.
lions are fun
My favorite thing about lion,
以及我输入的有关狮子的趣闻
lions are some of the most thoughtful writing partners in the world.
Lions are some of the most thoughtful writing partners in the world
You can see we're also still getting our data here, but most importantly,
在这里我们依然将数据打印出来 但更重要的是
we've updated our UI so that information that I just wrote and that we
我们使用用户输入和从
pulled dynamically from a Web API came together and updated onto our website.
Web API 获取的数据动态更新了页面
Now of course, you would do something much more creative than just having the text here.
当然 除了将文字显示在这里 你还可以增加一些创意
You could style it with CSS or you could add something like this, you could say,
你可以使用 CSS 美化页面 或者再增加点什么
lions are so endearing to young dogs on the run.
输入 lions are so endearing to young dogs on the run
So now we see the animal is Lion,
现在页面显示 Animal Is lion
which maybe makes a little more sense than lion.
这样看起来更好一点
But it's up to you because once you've done this,
这完全取决于你 一旦你加入元素
you have done elements that you are able to manipulate as is.
就可以动态更新它们
So for a second, let's forget about the HTML and let's go back to look at our JavaScript.
让我们暂时忘掉 HTML 回头看看 JavaScript 代码
So everything should look pretty familiar at the top.
上面这些代码应该都很熟悉了吧
This is our event listener.
这是事件监听器
This is our callback function.
这是回调函数
Now, we've selected the value of our fav box.
这里选择了 fav 元素
We make our call to the API.
我们先访问 API 获取数据
Then we post our data,
然后再 POST 更新数据
and this is the magic.
这是奇迹发生的地方
Because of async, we can wait until we have received the data,
因为是异步编程 我们可以等待数据返回后
posted the data, and then we can update our UI.
发起 POST 请求 然后再更新界面
If we go to our update UI,
再来看看 updateUI 函数
we see that that is also an async function which will request an all route.
这依然是一个异步函数 它向路由 all 发起请求
An all route we've set up on our server is very simple.
服务器端的路由 all 非常简单
We have app.getall with a callback function get data.
调用 app.get("/all") 并且传入一个回调函数提供数据
That is just going to send back to us, animal data.
然后将 animalData 返回
Animal data of course is also where our post route is set up to.
animalData 也是 POST 路由的数据端点
So on our post route,
在 POST 路由中
we're going to animal data.push the information we got as we've seen,
调用 animalData.push 保存信息
which populates animal data so that when we call it,
在需要时就可以从 animalData
it's ready for us.
中获取数据
Now, once we've got that data back,
拿到数据之后
which will wait for it to turn into JSON data,
我们将它转换为 JSON
then we can select the three elements that we want to update
然后用它更新
which just so you see correspond directly to here in my index.html,
index.html 中定义的三个元素
I have a div with the ID animal name,
一个 ID 为 animalName 的 div
a div with the ID animal fact,
一个 ID 为 animalFact 的 div
and a div with the ID animal fav.
一个 ID 为 animalFav 的 div
Here, I select each of those elements and then I
我依次选中这些元素
set the corresponding property which for us is innerHTML,
然后设置属性 innerHTML 的值
which is the property that it's going to set the text for us and then I
这个属性可以改变显示在页面上的文字
tell it what to do using.notation and brackets.
把数据取出来赋给它们就可以了
So all data is the variable that has our data in JSON format.
allData 保存了取回的数据
So from that, I want
从中取出
the zero index entry which is where you remember because it's zero index,
索引为 0 的元素
that's the first entry actually.
即第一个元素
For the animal name,
将 animal
I want to know what the animal is.
赋给 animalName
Then I want the facts and then fav.
然后依次取出 facts 和 fav
Of course, we set our error so that if anything goes wrong we'll know,
我们还打印出 error 这样出现错误时就知道了
but this would let us update our UI dynamically using change,
至此 我们使用了
fetch calls, and promises.
fetch 和 promises 动态更新了用户界面
Let's see it in action one more time now that we've gone over the code.
现在让我们再演示一遍
So lions, favorite things.
输入
Lions are so pretty in the morning.
Lions are so pretty in the morning
"I woke up like this,"
I woke up like this
says the yawning lion and action.
says the yawning lion
Magic, am I right?
见证奇迹的时候到了
So now we see how it all comes together by chaining promises and fetch calls.
我们学习了如何链接 promises 并使用 fetch
We're able to dynamically update the UI of our web app with asynchronous data calls.
动态更新用户界面